前情提要
黑客軍團
邪惡公司
留  著  我
機器人先生
泰瑞·科比被捕
ZiMuZu
傾情奉獻
小酸奶!   木淺   黑衣章魚X
翻譯
showeryhe   機器草
黑客軍團
第一季 第二集
兜兜兜爹
時間軸
Justin_R
寶寶
時間軸&后期&特效
校對
黑衣草
總監
草society
我要告訴你的事  是最高機密
What I'm about to tell you is top secret,
邪惡公司
Evil Corp.
提利爾·威利克
Tyrell Wellick.
你想一起嗑藥嗎
You want to do these together then?
純搖頭丸
Pure Molly...
不  夏拉
No, Shayla.
你得來趟眾安
I need you to come to AllSafe.
該死  他們進入網絡了
Shit. They're in the network?
就是這個  去社會
This is it. Fsociety.
他們叫我留著它
They're telling me to leave it here.
你是誰
Who are you?
我覺得你該跟我來
I think you should come with me.
嗯  那是達琳
Yeah, that's Darlene.
你要修改那個dat文件
You are going to modify the dat file
把科比的IP放進去
put Colby's IP in there.
你照做
You do that,
你就啟動了有史以來最大規模的革命
you have set in motion the largest revolution the world will ever see.
消息源確認黑客行為
sources have confirmed the hacks were
與科比的終端有一定關系
in part tied to Colby's terminal.
先生  請上車
Sir, step inside the car.
你好啊  艾略特
Bon soir, Elliot.
"給人一把槍  他就能搶銀行
"Give a man a gun and he can rob a bank,
但給人一座銀行  他就能洗劫整個世界"
but give a man a bank, and he can rob the world."
其實這說法挺蠢的
It's a bit of a silly expression, actually.
有點武斷了  但是...
A little reductive, but still...
我喜歡
I like it,
跟大部分人討厭這說法的原因一樣
for the same reason most people hate it,
因為我認為這話的意思是
because to me it means that
權力屬于肯去奪取的人
power belongs to the people that take it.
和他們的努力  強大的野心
Nothing to do with their hard work, strong ambitions,
或者資歷之類的都無關
or rightful qualifications, no.
通常  只有奪取的意愿才是最重要的
The actual will to take is often the only thing that's necessary.
很抱歉用這種方式把你帶過來
I'm sorry to bring you in like this.
嚴格說  我們這樣做可能是違法的
Technically what we're doing might be considered illegal,
所以我身邊才坐著
which is why I'm surrounded
11位最煩人的律師
by eleven of our most annoying lawyers.
艾略特·奧德森
Elliot Alderson...
我想為你提供
I want to offer you
邪惡公司供職的機會
a position here at Evil Corp.
我想要你來主管我們的網絡安全部
I want you to head our cybersecurity division.
但是由于我們和你的雇主  眾安
Except I can't officially offer you anything
有競業禁止協議  所以我不能正式聘用你
since we have this non-compete with your employer, Allsafe.
但如果你能自愿跳槽
But if you do this of your own accord--
你跳槽以后
when you do this--
五年內就能坐擁百萬家產
you'll be a multi-millionaire within the next five years.
你覺得怎么樣
What do you say?
我能...
Can I--
我能考慮一下嗎
Can I think about it?
先生們  讓我們單獨談談
Gentlemen, I need the room.
我知道  謝謝  謝謝
Yes, thank you. Yes, yes.
你知道嗎
You know,
邪惡公司剛任命我為臨時首席技術官
Evil Corp has just named me interim CTO.
過不了多久就會正式上任
It won't be long until it's official.
我將會成為這家公司有史以來最年輕的高管
I will be the youngest executive this company has ever seen.
我真應該找到那些黑客
I should track down these hackers out there
以表謝意
just to thank them.
這可以說有點...
In a way, it's kind of, um...
那個詞怎么說來著
What's the word in English?
誤打誤撞  對吧
Serendipitous? Right?
到本季度末
You know, by the end of the quarter,
我們準備重新構建網絡系統
we're going to revamp our entire network
并加固安全協議
and consolidate our security protocols.
所有事情我們都會內部解決
We're going to handle everything internally,
也就是說我們會中止和所有供應商的合同
which means all of our vendors, including Allsafe,
包括眾安
will be cut loose.
眾所周知  眾安沒了我們這個客戶
And it's no secret that once Allsafe loses us as a client,
就會完蛋
they'll be fini.
到了那時候
And when that happens,
我希望你能跟我一起在這里
I want you to be where you belong:
你屬于這里
here with me.
這個選擇非常重要  艾略特
This is an important choice you're making, Elliot.
我只是想在你做出最終決定之前
I just wanted you to know all the facts
讓你了解清楚情況
before you made your final decision.
我現在待在那兒很開心
I think I'm happy where I am.
我總得試試
Well, I thought I'd ask.
如果想聯系威利克先生就打這個電話
Call this number if you need to get in touch with Mr. Wellick.
你可以叫我X先生
You can call me Mr. X.
怎么  沒看過《刺殺肯尼迪》嗎
Come on, you've never seen JFK?
《刺殺肯尼迪》中的
神秘人物
奧利弗·斯通的那部
Oliver Stone movie?
先生  老實說  這太丟人了
Sir, I gotta be honest. That's embarrassing.
去看看那部電影吧  對你有好處
Do yourself a favor and watch it.
而且  老老實實付費吧
And pay, for Christ's sake.
你現在可以叫我薩瑟蘭先生
Anyway, you can call me Mr. Sutherland for now.
準備好了后不要猶豫  直接打給我
Don't hesitate to reach me when you're ready.
我們就在你附近
We're always close by.
我這就安排日子...
I'm gonna set a date right now--
-不要  -以供后用
- No, we're not. - For later.
我得走了  非常感謝
I gotta go, thank you very much.
-要我上去嗎  -不要
- You gonna have me up? - No.
-要邀請我上去嗎  -不要啦  住手
- Gonna have me up? - No, stop.
-我要上去  -不  你不能上去
- I'm coming up. - No, you're not coming up.
下次行嗎  我得走了
Another time. Okay, I gotta go.
別這樣
Come on.
-沒事吧  -沒事  他就是個變態
- Everything all right? - Yeah, he's just a creeper.
我最討厭不識趣的雇主了
I hate it when your employers can't take a hint.
你的散熱器壞了嗎
Hey, is your radiator messed up?
我房間里簡直是蒸籠
Because it's like 3,000 degrees in my apartment.
你沒事吧  你看起來有點不在狀態
Hey, are you okay? You seem off.
順便問問  能再給我一點嗎
While we're here, you mind if I reup?
現在就要有點早吧
A little early to reup, don't you think?
我有點偏離原計劃了
I'm deviating from the schedule a little.
沒想到你也有這一天啊  一絲不茍先生
Whoa, never thought I'd see the day, Mr. Stricty Pants,
不過行吧
but okie dokie.
該死  另一種用光了
Oh, yeah. Shit, I'm out of the other ones.
不  給我嗎啡就好
No, just the morphine. It's good.
不行  你讓我向你保證  賽寶松
Uh, no, you made me promise never to give you these
必須跟嗎啡一起給你的
unless I had your Subs.
-夏拉  -不  艾略特
- Shayla. - No, Elliot.
一諾千金
Promises matter, okay?
我很認真的
I take this shit to heart.
天吶
Oh, my God.
行吧  但你得保證在我幫你搞到戒癮藥之前
Fine, but you have to promise me you won't do a lot
你不會用太多
until I get your withdrawal meds, okay?
我稍后去找費爾南
I'll go see Fernando later or something.
不  你得說出來
No, you have to say it.
我保證
I promise.
伙計
Hey, man.
怎么了  你以為我忘掉你了嗎
What, you think I forgot about you?
相信我  我現在比以往更需要你
Trust me, I need you now more than ever.
得開始干活兒了
We gotta get to work.
黑提利爾·威利克按理說該是難事
Hacking Tyrell Wellick, you'd think it'd be tricky,
但并不是  邪惡公司的企業郵箱服務器
but it wasn't--Evil Corp's corporate mail servers,
自從《炮彈休克癥 》[1964]之后就再無改良了
they haven't patched anything since Shellshock.
甚至連雙步驗證登錄都不用
He doesn't even use two-step verification.
密碼不過是妻子的婚前姓
His password was just his wife's maiden name
加上瑞典的獨立日6月6號
and Sweden's independence date, 6-6.
再加個6就體現他們的邪惡本質了[666是魔鬼]
One six away from the obvious, but still,
但也還是未免太簡單
this is bad noob practice.
郵箱代理
這些郵件
These emails...
他的生活  美好  幸福  完美
His life... it's nice, happy, perfect.
提利爾·威利克
提利爾的照片
毫無道理
This doesn't make sense.
難道他知道我會黑他
Did he know I was going to hack him?
這是圈套嗎
Did he let me?
我得把一切都銷毀
I'm gonna need to wipe everything.
我知道  我知道  嗑多了
I know, I know, taking more than I should.
我壞了規矩  但這周就是不正常嘛
I'm breaking my rule, but come on, it's an off week.
快點
Come on.
伙計  你得
My man, you gotta--
你得在這兒解決  好嗎
You gotta deuce it out over here, all right?
你得在這兒解手  好嗎
Yo, you gotta do your business up in here, all right?
你能行的  你能行的
You got this. You got this.
泰瑞·科比  首席技術官...
Terry Colby, the chief technology officer of--
泰瑞·科比被捕的消息占據了大家的注意
Terry Colby's arrest is on everyone's mind.
和屏幕  如今這兩者也沒區別了
Screen. Might as well be the same thing nowadays.
泰瑞·科比被捕撼動技術世界
發生了這事我還要怎么繼續工作啊
How do I go back to work after this?
還怎么能集中注意呢
How can I focus on anything?
機器人先生什么時候才會再聯系我啊
And when's Mr. Robot going to contact me again?
他在等什么
What's he waiting for?
我不會是白白毀掉了一個人的生活吧
Did I just destroy a man's life for no reason?
我會跟人力資源說給你加薪
I'm gonna talk to HR about a salary bump for you.
-不用了  -不不
- Oh, please. - No, no.
你就接受吧
Take the raise.
不會很多  但目前我也只能做這么多
It's not gonna be much, but it's the best I can do right now.
艾略特
Elliot...
你救了公司
You saved the company.
我想知道
Now...
你為什么沒告訴我dat文件的事
Why didn't you tell me about the dat file?
會議之前你完全可以來我這里
You could've come in here at any time before the meeting
告訴我你有了發現  但你沒有
to say you found something, but you didn't.
說實話  我覺得這有點奇怪啊
I gotta be honest. I found that kind of curious.
我當時也不知道自己發現了什么
Yeah, I didn't know what I had.
也可能是垃圾文件呢
Could've easily been a junk file.
好啦
C'mon...
你從不下定論
You're never sure about anything
除非是真有問題
unless there's something to be sure about.
也許你并沒那么了解我
Maybe you don't know me that well.
不論如何
Regardless,
你還得繼續負責他們  現在更為重要了
I still need you to stay on it, now more than ever.
誰知道那些去社會的黑客接下來會干什么呢
I mean, who knows what these fsociety hackers are going to do next.
他說什么
What did he just say?
-你說什么  -科比手下那些
- What did you just say? - The ones working with Colby.
誰知道數據公布會達到什么程度
Who knows how deep these data dumps are going to get,
而且邪惡公司
and Evil Corp is--
你在說什么呢
What're you talking about?
真是難得
There's a twist.
一般都是你比我消息靈通
You're usually the one a step ahead of me.
入侵時  他們挖到了金礦
They hit the mother lode during the breach.
可能盜取了兆位級的郵件和文件
Potentially terabytes worth of emails and files.
他們威脅聯調局釋放科比
They're threatening to dump everything
否則就拋出所有文件
unless the FBI frees Colby.
今天早上發布了視頻
They released the video this morning.
邪惡公司黑客入侵并未結束
你好  邪惡公司  我們是去社會
Hello, Evil Corp. We are fsociety.
這些年來  我們一直在關注你
Over the years, we have been watching you.
你金融欺詐窮人
Your financial abuse of the poor;
腐敗政府官員
your corruption of governments;
掩蓋對無辜平凡市民的謀殺
your cover-ups of the murder of innocent, ordinary citizens,
為利潤干不惜一切
all for the sake of a profit.
所以我們去社會決定你們必須被鏟除
This is why we at fsociety have decided you must die.
我們是有惡意的  是敵意的  我們不會妥協
We are malicious and hostile. We do not compromise.
我們不會留情
We are relentless.
我們決不罷手  直到斬斷
We will not stop until every tentacle
你的每一根邪惡觸角
of your evil monstrosity is sliced off at the nerve.
但我們也并非不通情理
But we are also not without mercy.
上次的入侵是最后的警告
Our latest hack was our last warning.
滿足要求  我們就考慮不毀掉你們
Meet our demands, and we will consider not destroying you.
首先  結束你們的非法囚禁
First, release our leader Terry Colby
立刻釋放我們的領袖泰瑞·科比
from your illegitimate prison immediately.
第二  撤銷你們給世界上
Second, release all the people of the world
無辜平民加諸的非法債務
from your even more illegitimate prisons of debt.
第三  解散你們公司
Third, dissolve your corporation
把資產全部捐給世界各地的慈善機構
and donate all your assets to charities around the world.
紐約證券交易所
我們的要求不可協商
This proposal is non-negotiable.
占領華爾街
人們已經意識到只要有你們
The people are realizing they don't have freedom of choice
他們就不會有自由選擇權
so long as you exist.
人們在覺醒
The people are waking up,
人民拒絕成為你們的經濟奴隸
no longer accepting your economic slavery.
釋放阿桑奇
立即滿足我們的要求  否則就滅了你們
Meet these demands, or we will kill you.
警告送達  看著辦吧
Consider yourself warned.
去社會
再放一遍
Play it again.
走過路過不要錯過  我的專輯出爐了
Yo, yo, yo, yo, my album just dropped.
快來買張CD吧  價格只要20塊
Yo, please buy my CD. Only cost you 20 likes.
保證你聽得爽  我跟你保證
Yo, it'll give you the feels, y'all, I swear.
你要是發個推  我就免費送專輯
The CD's free. All's I ask is you Tweet.
幫我上頭條吧
Help my social media outreach.
我當時就想  "我想安排這次見面
You know, be like, "I want to set up this meeting.
這是個非常非常..."
It's like a very, like a--"
艾略特
Oh, Elliot!
恭喜啊  哥們
Hey, congrats, man.
多謝了你  眾安在網上都紅爆了
Allsafe is all over the internet today because of you.
該慶祝一下啊  哥們  我們團購了周四的
Dude, we should celebrate. We have this Groupon
莫爾頓牛排坊四人餐
for four at Morton's on Thursday.
另外說好的一對突然就不來了
This other couple we were going with totally bailed.
不如你替他們去吃
Why don't you come with?
他們牛排爆好吃  29.95塊就能
Their steaks are badass. It's $29.95--
我覺得艾略特不會有興趣的
I'm not sure that Elliot would like that.
嗯  好
Yeah, okay.
你同意  太好了老兄
Yeah? Okay. Awesome, man.
不如我們搞個四人約會算了
And, hey, why don't we make it a double date?
我聽說你有了個女友
I heard that you had a girlfriend.
奧利  你怎么能說出來呢
Ollie, you weren't supposed to say anything.
親愛的  沒關系  艾略特不介意的
Babe, it's cool. Elliot's okay with it.
嗯  好  可以  我得走了
Yeah, okay, sure. I--have to go.
我鄰居又抱怨我的狗狂叫了
Um, my neighbor's complaining about the dog barking again.
他什么時候養狗了
Since when does he have a dog?
你們倆一對璧人兒啊
You look like a beautiful couple.
我的專輯剛發行
Yo, my album just dropped,
你喜歡說唱  嘻哈嗎
You like rap, hip-hop?
我這歌可有深度了  歌詞又好聽
Yo, this shit is deep, lyrical, poetic.
你女友肯定喜歡  肯定的
Yo, your girl will like this, my man, I swear.
老兄  你在我們大樓外邊都轉悠了半個月了
Come on, bro, you've been outside our building for two weeks now.
那好吧  我買了
All right, you know, I'll take it,
你能別纏著我們嗎
if you leave us alone.
謝謝您  太謝謝你了大哥
Thank you, thank you, man, thank you.
而且我聽著順耳才會發推  明白嗎
And I'll tweet, but only if I like it, all right?
我只有48個粉  不過還在穩步增長
I only have 48 followers, but it's growing.
-當然當然  -其中有人品味很好
- No doubt, no doubt. - Some tastemakers in there so--
我懂  我懂
I feel you, I feel you.
-行  -那好
- Yeah. - All right.
太謝謝你了  真的
Yo, I appreciate it, man, really.
-祝你們一天順順當當的  -你也是
- You guys have a good day. - Yeah, you too.
多謝你們  聽聽第二首
Thank you so much. Check track two out.
-第二首  -回見哥們
- Track two. - All right, man.
這可是計劃外狀況
This was never part of the plan.
公布數據  還要釋放泰瑞·科比
Data dumps? Releasing Terry Colby?
根本說不通
None of this makes sense.
我得和去社會撇清關系
Need to cut off all ties with fsociety.
再不和他們聯系
Need to disconnect.
我得請個病假  暫時低調...
We need to call in sick and lie low for a--
有病啊你  我光著呢  混蛋
Dude! Jesus Christ! I am naked, asshole!
瞅什么瞅
Don't stare at me!
你怎么在我家洗澡
Why the hell are you in my shower?
我本來在等你
Well, I was waiting for you.
你昨晚該來的
You were supposed to come last night.
-你忘了  -來  來哪里
- Did you forget? - Come? Where?
無所謂了  大家待會兒會去
It's fine, everyone's coming later.
我順你幾件衣服穿
I'm stealing your clothes.
有人射在我的衣服上了
My dress has cum stains on it.
天啊  我逗你玩呢
Jesus, I am just messing with you.
我的衣服在洗衣機里
My stuff is just in the wash.
洗好之前先穿一會兒你的衣服
I'm gonna borrow this for the time being.
對了
Oh, by the way,
你的狗在你床上拉屎了
your dog shat on your bed.
狗是得出去溜的
You gotta walk that thing.
麻煩你幫我照看小鰭一下吧
Hey, please take Flipper for a while.
她可能得帶出去溜溜
She probably needs a walk or something.
到處拉屎
She keeps shitting everywhere.
當然得溜啊  艾略特
Of course she needs a walk, Elliot.
她是條狗
She's a friggin' dog.
我們出發之前我想吃點兒酸奶
Yo, I want to stop and get some froyo before we go.
我待會兒就回
Uh, I'll be back later.
-我欠你個人情  -大人情
- I owe you. - Yeah, big time.
你怎么知道我住哪
How do you know where I live?
我怎么就不能知道你住哪
Why wouldn't I know where you live?
不知道  我就不知道你住哪
I don't know. I don't know where you live.
我目前也沒個固定住處
I don't live anywhere at the present.
我約會的那傻子跟我求婚了  你相信嗎
The douche I was dating proposed to me, can you believe?
整個一混蛋嘛
I mean, what an asshole.
總之我們大吵了一架  然后
Anyways, we got into this huge fight, and--
我在磨蹭什么呢
What the hell am I doing?
這個妞兒完全就是個瘋子
This chick is out of her mind batshit crazy.
我得趕緊回去  把一切都告訴吉迪恩
I gotta go back, tell Gideon everything.
他會理解的  對吧
He'll understand, right?
他會知道怎么辦的
He'll know what to do.
沒關系的  他會來找我的
It's whatevs. He'll take me back.
他得趁早戒了那一套
He's just gotta get over this whole
"愛你到永遠"之類的屁話
"Love is forever" bullshit.
我先躲一陣
I'll do my disappearing act for a minute,
然后他就會想通了
and then he'll come to his senses.
-車門關閉  注意安全  -我們就這樣
- Stand clear of the closing door. - You know, it's our thing.
快點
Quick!
她也能看到他們嗎
Can she see them, too?
怎么了
What?
我喜歡臨時起意
I like to stay on my toes.
說到那個  那簡直煩人死了...
Speaking of, that's, like, one of the most annoying things--
但如果提利爾發現了  他會怎么做
But what if Tyrell finds out? What will he do?
倒霉  除了被殺和坐牢
Shit, there's basically no scenario in which
基本上沒別的可能
I'm not getting killed or going to jail.
我想要只海龜  他就不讓
Because I wanted a turtle, and he was like, "No--"
我大概要跟你待兩晚
I might need to crash with you for a couple of nights.
沒事吧
That's cool, right?
不是吧
Seriously?
好吧  那我去莫布利家
Fine! I'll crash at Mobley's.
反正我也不喜歡狗
Don't love dogs anyway.
特別是你在你床上拉屎的
Especially ones that shit in your bed.
你那樣怎么住得下去
I mean, how do you live like that, honestly?
你怎么睡得著...
How do you go to sleep when you know that there's...
目前看來
For all we know,
我可能正步入一個圈套
I could be walking into a trap right now.
一旦走進那扇門  我們可能就會沒命
We could be dead the second I walk through that door.
快跟上  小子  有大事等著我們
Come on, kid. We got big things in store.
大事
Big things.
風云人物  行個屈膝禮吧
Man of the hour. Take a curtsy.
臭鴨子
Goddamn ducks.
哥們
Hey, hey, man!
那個...倒霉  抱歉  伙計
What's... Oh. Shit, sorry, sorry, dude.
好吧
Um, okay.
總之  干得漂亮  兄弟
Anyway, just, awesome work, man.
超棒
Really awesome.
厲害  哥們  厲害
Right on, man. Right on.
-超厲害  -好啦
- Real cool. - Great.
我們已經相互拍了馬屁
So now that we're all done going down on each other,
能了解一下計劃嗎
can we please hear the plan?
鋼山那邊現在進展如何
Where are we at with Steel Mountain?
如果沒弄錯
If I'm not mistaken,
那些線路還不是百分百安全
these lines aren't 100% safe yet,
我們還沒能讓科比項目消失
and we still haven't made the Colby project disappear.
不是吧
Seriously?
都過去幾周了  有任何連接或線索
It's been weeks. Any links or traces
現在早該被掌握了
would have been owned by now.
線路上無跡可尋  老大  我發誓
The lines are clean, Boss, I swear.
-謝謝  -我想...
- Thank you. - I mean, um...
如果能讓你安心點  羅梅洛和我可以檢查...
if it makes you feel better, Romero and I can check...
很好  這我就安心多了
Great! Make me feel great.
我去那邊待著  整理一下思路
I'm gonna hang back over here, collect my thoughts.
她怎么回事
What's her deal?
這女人很難懂
Ah, she's a complicated woman.
大多寫惡意軟件的碼農都這樣  對吧
Most malware coders are. Am I right?
她跑去了我公寓
She showed up at my apartment.
她怎么知道我住哪
Why does she know where I live?
別管她了
Let's not focus on her.
否則會像嗑嗨醒不過來一樣
That'll be like entering a bad K-hole you'll never wake up from.
你該關注我們項目的下一階段
Instead, I need you to focus on the next phase of our project.
彗星  奧爾巴尼的那個天然氣工廠  知道嗎
Comet, the natural gas plant up around Albany?
我們打算把它炸了
We're gonna blow it up.
為什么要炸...
Why would you blow...
彗星工廠就在鋼山旁邊
Comet plant's right next to Steel Mountain.
如你所知
Which, as you know,
是標準普爾所有公司
is the off-site and data storage facility
外部數據存儲中心
for every corporation in the S&P,
包括大家的最愛
including everyone's favorite--
-邪惡公司  -沒錯
- Evil Corp. - Bingo!
你打算破壞他們的磁帶備份
You're gonna destroy their tape backups.
他們肯定在提防這種事
They're gonna be looking out for something like that.
被黑后就變得高度警覺了
They've been on high alert ever since the hack.
據說已經抓到那個黑客了
From what I heard, they've caught their hacker.
-不是嗎  -沒有
- Haven't they? - No, they haven't.
-提利爾·威利克知道了  -只知道想讓他知道的
- Tyrell Wellick knows. - What they want him to know!
他和其他人一樣不過是公司機器人
He's a corporate robot just like the rest of them.
而且整個公司都要
Besides, the entire company is gonna be reeling
應付我們準備的數據公布了
from all the data dumps we've got in store for them--
我們有不少好東西呢
and man, do we have some goodies.
老式高管種族歧視
Some good old-fashioned executive racism,
性別歧視  法西斯主義
sexism, Fascism.
相信我  我們會拿各種麻煩淹沒他們
Trust me, we are gonna "ism" so much all over them
讓他們暈頭轉向
they won't be able to see straight.
要求釋放科比這點很聰明
And asking for Colby's release as ransom was genius.
這只會讓他更受關注
That'll only make his spotlight bigger,
我們不會被發現
keeping it off us.
那個小花招是特倫頓的主意
That neat little ditty was Trenton's idea.
她看起來無害  但可別小瞧她
She may look innocent, but I'd be careful.
她的神力不小呢
She's got some Allah Akbar in her.
我們搞這些的同時
And while all that's going on,
你要用你的眾安安全權限
you will use your Allsafe security clearance
黑進彗星的壓力控制  增加壓強
to hack the Comet PLC, increase the pressure,
造成天然氣管道爆炸
causing a gas pipeline explosion
讓鋼山和邪惡公司的數據一起炸飛
making Steel Mountain go kablooey along with Evil Corp's soul.
他們都知道這個
They know about all this?
你是第一個
You're the first.
那些工人
Workers?
住在工廠附近的居民
Anyone living around the plant...
他們都會死
They all die?
我們會讓他們先跑
We'll give them a head start.
鳴響警報之類的  他們會沒事
Sound some alarms. They'll be fine.
你要炸一根天然氣管道
You're blowing up a gas pipeline.
這個世界本來就很危險  艾略特
The world is a dangerous place, Elliot,
不是因為干壞事的人
not because of those who do evil,
而是因為那些圍觀無作為的人
but because of those who look on and do nothing.
這是戰爭
This is war.
會死人的  死亡難以避免
People will die. C'est la mort.
等我們炸了管線
And once we blow up the pipeline,
達琳的蠕蟲會在美國數據中心
Darlene's worm will kick into high gear
開始加速運轉
at the U.S. Data center
這還是你幫忙裝的  多謝了
which you helped to us install, thank you very much.
遠在中國的東方數據中心的冗余備份
The redundant backups at their eastern data center in China--
有黑暗軍團幫我們
the Dark Army is covering us on that.
黑暗軍團  為什么啊
Dark Army? Why, man?
他們毫無準則  為任何人做雇傭黑客
They got no code. They hack for anyone:
恐怖分子  北朝  伊朗  俄國
terrorists, North Korea, Iran, Russia--
所以說他們也痛恨美國資本主義
Which means they hate U.S. capitalism just as much as anyone.
還有一點
Last but not least.
鋼山
Steel Mountain.
黑客困境
The hacker's dilemma.
你如何摧毀完全
What to do when a bunch of data you want to destroy
不聯網的數據
is completely off the grid?
我不會殺人的
I'm not killing anyone.
告訴我  艾略特
Tell me one thing, Elliot.
你是1還是0
Are you a one or a zero?
你要問自己這個問題
That's the question you have to ask yourself.
你是是還是否
Are you a yes or a no?
你是要采取行動  還是無所作為
Are you going to act or not?
你是玩電腦
Yo...you've been staring at a computer screen
玩太久了  朋友
way too long, homie.
生活不是那么二進制的
Life's not that binary.
是嗎
Isn't it?
是啊  有灰色地帶
Sure, there are grays--
但說到底  最根本
but when you come right down to it, at its core,
每個決定  都是由1或0構成
beneath every choice, there's either a one or a zero.
你要么采取行動  要么什么不做
You either do something or you don't.
你走出那扇門  就是決定了要什么都不做
You walk out that door, you've decided to do nothing,
決定拒絕  那么你就不能再回來了
to say no, which means you do not come back.
你走  就不再是這事的一員了
You leave, you are no longer a part of this.
你就是0了
You become a zero.
如果你留下
If you stay,
如果你想改變世界
if you want to change the world,
你就選擇了同意
you become a yes.
你就是1
You become a one.
我再問你一次
So, I'll ask you again:
你是1還是0
are you a one or a zero?
我做的事導致一個無辜者入獄
An innocent man is in prison because of what I did.
得了  別自欺欺人了
Come on, let's not kid ourselves!
這跟科比毫無關系
This has nothing to do with Colby.
甚至跟我的革命都無關
This isn't even about my revolution.
對你不僅是如此
This is more than that for you.
你是為了那些混蛋慢慢地殺了你父親
This is about how those bastards slowly killed your father
而你希望他當初對此采取了行動
and how you wished he'd done something about it.
但他沒有  因為他是0
But he didn't. Because he was a zero,
就像你現在這樣
just like you're being right now.
去你的
F--- you.
又要玩消失嗎
Disappearing again?
我不殺人  你們別扯上我
I'm not killing anyone. Leave me out of this.
這事你躲不過
You don't get to disappear from this.
有沒有你我們都會做
We can do it with or without you,
但你無論如何都已經參與了
but you're a part of it either way!
就算你的傻逼兜帽也保護不了你  賤人
Yeah, even your stupid hoodie can't protect you, bitch!
這就是個錯誤
This was a mistake.
我得告發他們  我該告發他們嗎
I've gotta turn them in. Should I turn them in?
我會惹上麻煩嗎  該死  她說得有理
Will I get into trouble? Shit, she's right.
我現在也有罪了  不  是我們有罪
I'm culpable now. No, we're culpable.
你跟我是一起的了  趕緊想辦法吧
You're in this with me, so start thinking of solutions now.
夏拉
Shayla?
Yo, Shayla.
伙計
Yo, bro.
需要什么嗎
Can I help you with something?
我就是想跟夏拉談談
I, uh...just need to talk to Shayla.
你女人啊
Oh, your girl.
她在浴缸里呢
She in the tub.
夏拉
Shayla.
她待會兒就出來了
Yo, she'll be out in a minute.
你想的話坐下等會兒吧
Can sit and wait if you want.
我們還是進去看看吧  確保她沒事
I think we should check on her, make sure she's all right.
你真逗  我喜歡你
You a funny dude. I like you.
別那么沒禮貌
Don't be rude.
坐下  待會兒
Sit down and chill.
不用了
No, that's right.
你只嗑這個
You only do this.
就認識你一個一邊嗑藥一邊用戒癮藥的
Only nigga I know that take withdrawal meds while he using.
很聰明
That's smart.
是不是還騙自己說你不是個癮君子
Probably even convinced yourself you ain't an addict.
該死
Oh, shit.
都忘記自我介紹了  我是費南...
Forgot to introduce myself. I'm Fernan--
費南多·維拉  夏拉的毒販
Fernando Vera, Shayla's supplier.
我黑過的最渣的人之一
One of the worst human beings I've ever hacked.
他的密碼  吃屌6969[體位]
His password? "Eatadick6969."
不僅在色情片和網絡攝像頭上花了很多錢
Aside from the massive amounts of money he spends on porn and webcams,
他的毒品交易還都是通過電郵  網聊和推特做的
he does all his drug transactions through emails, IMs, Twitter.
警方居然還沒逮到他  簡直難以理解
The fact that the cops haven't caught him yet is beyond me.
如果他們有點腦子
If they had half a brain cell,
早就該能破解他們團伙超級簡單的密文
they'd be able to crack his gang's simplistic code,
如果那算得上密文的話
if it can even be called that.
花了幾小時理清他發布的推文
After only a couple of hours of timing his tweets
和相關新聞報道的時間線
with related news articles,
我便搞明白"餅干"和"咔嗒"
I figured out that "biscuit" and "clickety"
顯然是指槍
clearly referenced guns.
"食物""貝殼"或"汽油"是子彈
"Food," "sea shells" or "gas" for bullets.
還有最狠的  "早早哄入睡"
And the ultimate: "Rock to sleep early."
我還沒直接與那起命案聯系起來
I haven't made the direct connection to a hit yet,
但槍支加上子彈
but the math of guns plus bullets
一般只有一種結果
usually adds up to one thing.
我考慮過告發他
I've thought about turning him in,
但他是夏拉唯一的供毒販
but he's Shayla's only supplier.
我扳倒他  我也沒藥了
I take him down, I lose my drugs,
現在有那么多事  我不能失去藥
and with everything going on right now, I can't have that.
你懂的吧
You get that, though?
總之  伙計
Anyway, bro,
不用擔心我
I ain't nothing to worry about.
就是來給你送貨的
Just making a drop for you.
你叫什么
What's your name, anyway?
艾略特
Elliot.
什么意思
What it mean?
你從沒谷歌過嗎
What, you ain't never Googled it?
得去谷歌啊
Man, you gotta do that.
一個人名字的含義是很重要的  伙計
The meaning of a person's name is important, bro.
她沒事的  她沒事
Yo, she good! She good.
相信我
Trust me.
我親自確保的
Took care of that shit myself.
你讓我想起了我年輕一點的時候
You remind me of me when I was younger,
壓抑  陰沉
depressed and sullen.
事實上  我還曾幾次試圖自殺
Matter of fact, tried to kill myself, a couple of times.
一直沒做對
Never could get that shit right.
生物不是我的強項
Biology wasn't my strong suit.
我恨自己  現在也是
I hated myself, man. Still do.
很久以來  覺得那是軟弱
Thought that shit was a weakness for a long time.
然后我意識到  那是我的力量
Then I realized that shit was my power.
這世上的人  一副知道恨是什么的樣子
People walk around, act like they know what hate means.
不  沒人知道  除非你恨自己
Nah, no one does, until you hate yourself.
我是指
I mean...
真正恨自己
truly hate yourself.
那才是力量
That's power.
你不怕我吧
You ain't scared of me, are you?
很好
That's good.
那我就不用浪費時間討好你了
Means I didn't waste my time making friends with you.
你并不需要這個吧
You don't really need these, do you?
你這么勇敢的人  能撐過戒癮的
Man of your courage can last through a little withdrawal.
就是因為你  我才認識夏拉
Ya know, you the only reason why I met Shayla.
我是市內唯一什么都賣的人
I'm the only nigga in town carrying everything,
包括你的寶貝賽寶松
including your precious Suboxone.
所以  說來怪  但我該感謝你
So, in a weird way, I should be thanking you.
是你把她送到我身邊
You brought her to me.
你的行星環繞我
Your star orbiting with mine, gravitationally,
給我帶來了我的摯愛  艾略特
brought me the love of my life, Elliot.
我們這樣
I mean, this, us?
在這里相見
Being here?
這擁有
This has...
美妙的意義
beautiful meaning.
但別誤會  那女孩
But make no mistake, that girl in there...
是我的
is mine.
離了她我都不知道如何是好
I don't know what I'd do without her.
我不知道你們之前
Now, I don't know what kind of arrangement
有怎樣的安排  但既然我們都是朋友了
you had with her before, but now that we friends...
相信你會知道朋友妻不可欺
I trust you respect this boundary.
懂嗎
Feel me?
今天早些時候也有個家伙這么看我
A dude earlier today gave me that same look.
我只想說
Only thing I gotta say is,
有時候  還是害怕明智  伙計
there's a smart time to be scared, bro...
也有時不明智
and a stupid time.
夏拉
Shayla?
撬鎖
The lock pick.
所有黑客最鐘情的運動
Every hacker's favorite sport.
最合適去破解的系統
The perfect system to crack,
主要是因為與虛擬系統不同
mostly because unlike virtual systems,
你撬開它時  你能感覺到
when you break it, you can feel it.
能看到  能聽到
You can see it. You can hear it.
夏拉
Shayla.
醒醒
Wake up.
怎么回事
What happened?
你沒事吧
You okay?
那混蛋怎么在這兒
Why was that asshole here?
我怎么在浴缸里
Why am I in the tub?
我不知道  我告訴他  我需要你的藥
I don't know, um...I told him I needed your pills.
他就過來  我們抽了一會兒
He came over. We smoked a little.
你記得跟他做愛嗎
You remember having sex with him?
什么  不
What? No.
但他肯定記得
But he definitely does.
好吧  走吧
Okay, let's go.
-拿上你的包  一定...  -別說了
- Get your purse, make sure-- - Stop.
我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere, okay?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你要讓他逃脫罪責嗎
Oh, he's just gonna get away with it?
你不能再去找他了  我不需要那些藥
You can't go back to him. Hey, I don't need the pills.
-找別人試試吧  -我不能
- Just find someone else. - I can't.
他給我的價錢很便宜
He gives me a really good deal on the split.
我掙錢多
I make good money.
又來了
There it is again,
那個隱形之手在控制我們
the invisible hand at work, controlling us,
即使推我們越過了疼痛臨界點
even if it pushes us past our threshold of pain.
這不會停止的
It's not gonna stop.
如果他再這么做呢
What if he does it again?
答應我你不會做任何事
Promise me you won't do anything?
我說真的  艾略特
I'm serious, Elliot.
沒什么可做的
There's nothing to be done here.
我又沒什么選擇
It's not like I have a choice.
你今晚能睡這里嗎
Would you mind sleeping here tonight?
選擇
Choices.
或許機器人先生是對的
Maybe Mr. Robot's right.
這才是一切的關鍵  生活中的同意和拒絕
That's what this is all about, the yesses and nos of life.
但是我們做決定  還是決定左右我們
But do we decide them or do they decide us?
費南多·維拉  我解決了他
Fernando Vera. I get rid of him,
也就斷了我自己的毒品源
I get rid of my drug dealer's supplier.
也就斷了嗎啡
I get rid of the morphine.
我一直在控制的痛苦會一擁而上
And the pain I've been holding in comes rushing out.
是啊  我可以再去找其他毒販
Sure, I can try to find another dealer,
但就像維拉所說  街面上沒人賣賽寶松
but like Vera said, no one on the streets deals Suboxone.
我可以回到電子偽造處方的手段
I could go back to digitally counterfeiting scripts,
但藥房都花大錢保護他們的商品
but pharmas spend a lot of dough protecting their wares.
大部分地方只收紙質處方
Most places only take paper scripts.
想一直拿到合法的處方是不現實的
Continuously getting legit refills isn't realistic,
做癮君子也一樣
and neither is being a junkie.
所以  我要么直接戒斷  要么就放過維拉
So I quit cold turkey or let Vera exist.
我知道你在想什么  答案太簡單了
I know what you're thinking. The answer's too obvious.
維拉之前或許已經對夏拉動手動腳
Vera may have been groping Shayla before,
但現在他已經升級至強奸了
but he's graduated to rape.
費南多·維拉  早早哄入睡
跟夏拉一樣  他讓我別無選擇
Just like Shayla, he's left me no choice.
不能允許他再逍遙了
He can't be allowed to exist anymore.
我們先說說你的感受吧
Perhaps we should start with how you're feeling.
不太好
Not good.
現在什么不太好
What's not good right now?
都不好
Everything.
跟我說說細節吧
Humor me with some specifics.
你要如何知道你能掌控生活
How do we know if we're in control?
而不是對生活的困難
That we're not just making the best
盡力而為  僅此而已
of what comes at us, and that's it.
總是在兩個選項中二選其一
Trying to constantly pick between two options.
就像你等候室里的兩幅畫
Like your two paintings in the waiting room.
或是  可樂還是百事
Or...Coke and Pepsi.
麥當勞還是漢堡王
McDonald's or Burger King?
現代還是本田
Hyundai or Honda?
費南多·維拉
都是模糊一片  不是嗎
It's all part of the same blur, right?
唐人街暴力沖突升級  黑幫分子被殺
剛好對不上焦
Just out of focus enough.
紐約警局匿名檢舉熱線
只是有選擇的幻覺
It's the illusion of choice.
維拉
我們半數人  甚至不能自己選
Half of us can't even pick our own--
點擊"瀏覽"選擇文件與檢舉一同發送
有線電視  煤氣  電力
our cable, gas, electric.
多謝你協助保護紐約市安全
我們喝的水  我們的醫療保險
The water we drink, our health insurance.
就算是我們選的  又有什么用
Even if we did, would it matter?
如果我們只能在藍十字會和藍盾[均為醫療保險]中選擇
You know, if our only option is Blue Cross or Blue Shield,
那又有什么差別
what the f--- is the difference?
而且  這倆不是一樣的嗎
In fact, aren't they-- aren't they the same?
不
No, man...
我們的選擇早已經有定數了
our choices are prepaid for us,
早就選好了
long time ago.
很遺憾你感到無法控制
I'm sorry you feel you have no control.
我以為我在做好事
Thought I was doing something good.
我參與了一個項目
I was a part of this... project.
我以為我參與了一件特別的事
Thought I was going to be a part of something special.
現在呢
And now?
現在
Now...
原來那是個錯誤
It turned out to be a mistake,
就像其他的一切
like everything else.
有什么意義
What's the point, right?
真不如  什么都不做
Might as well, just-- you do nothing.
不如什么都不做
Might as well do nothing.
你以前也提過這個問題
You've brought up this issue before,
感覺你無法控制
this issue of not feeling like you're in control.
記得嗎
Do you remember?
那是我們聊你父親的時候
When we spoke about your father.
你說他抗擊癌癥時
You talked about how he chose to do nothing
選擇了無所作為
when he was battling his cancer.
你跟他說  他可以起訴導致他得癌的公司
You told him he could have fought the company that caused it.
他可以把這事說出去
He could have told people about it.
他可以尋求更好的治療
He could have sought better care than what he was getting.
但他什么都沒做
Instead, he did nothing.
或許你父親當時的感覺跟你現在一樣
Maybe your father felt the same way as you do now.
畢竟  就像你說的  有什么意義呢
After all, like you said, what's the point?
-這不一樣  -不一樣的是
- It's different. - What's different
你找到了選擇  艾略特
is you've found options, Elliot.
這是你擁有的權力  你擁有的控制權
That's the power you have. That's the control you own.
你不想單純接受生活的安排
You don't have to just take what life gives you.
說吧
Come on.
告訴我你究竟是怎么了
Tell me what is going on with you.
你不告訴我  我沒法幫你
I cannot help you if you keep me in the dark.
別說了
Shut up!
你有黑眼圈
You've got bags under your eyes.
你在大喊  你煩躁不安
You're yelling. You're jittery.
這幾個月來  我看著你
For the last month, I have seen you
漸漸回歸老路子  以前的行為
slip into old patterns, old behaviors.
到底怎么樣了
What is going on?
刻錄  費南多·維拉
刪除
工業氣候控制白皮書
室內溫度控制
他還是不接
He's still not answering.
那我們明天問他吧
Well, we'll just have to ask him tomorrow.
我每次播放這東西
Every time I try to play it or rip it,
就只是卡住我的電腦  然后再彈出
it just freezes up my computer and spits it back out again.
他不太好
He's not okay.
他今天在公司根本心不在焉
He was acting so out of it at work today.
斯黛拉·B  你得馬上看看
今晚過來吧
我盡量  待會兒打給你
你說什么
Are you saying something, babe?
他不對勁
Something's wrong.
我該過去看看嗎
Should I go over there?
就是去
And just...
看看他
Check in on him?
得了
Uh...come on.
別傻了
That's ridiculous.
你知道他一直都是個怪人
You know he's always been a weirdo, right?
我真心擔心他
I'm really worried about him.
我亞利桑那州的朋友弗萊德找到了我
My Arizona buddy Fred hit me up.
他想跟我喝一杯
He wants to grab a drink.
不會太久的
Shouldn't take too long.
好
Okay.
進去了
"深深的激情和渴望...
"Deep passions, longing...
他們兩人從未感受到過這般的愛
the two of them had never felt such a love,
如此親昵  如此心有靈犀"
such closeness, such a connection."
我有辦法不用...
Found a way to do it without--
坐
Sit down.
我知道要如何摧毀備份
I know how to take out the backups
而不必炸管線了
without blowing up the pipeline.
艾略特  這事我們不是
You know, Elliot, I really feel like we resolved
已經解決了嗎  你不是退出了嗎
this thing between us. Didn't you walk away?
是啊
I did.
我不是說  你如果走掉
Didn't I say that if you walked away,
你就不再是這件事的一員了
you were no longer a part of this?
我想好了一個計劃
I have a real plan--
如果你想要我再允許你加入
If you want me to let you back in,
我們得達成一定共識
there's an understanding we have to come to,
你得還個債
a debt you have to pay,
別忘了  是你退出了
because, remember, you walked away.
你不是不信債務這回事嗎
I thought you didn't believe in debts.
不是的  我相信債務
Not true. I believe in debts.
我相信該消除債務
I believe in erasing them.
你想怎么樣
What do you want?
我要你跟我說說你父親
I want you to tell me about your father.
你別想探究我的心理
You're not gonna get into my head, man.
少給我洗腦
Your David Koresh shit isn't gonna work on me.
跟我說說他是怎么死的
Tell me how he died.
有什么意義  我覺得
Why, man? Something tells me
你已經查過了
you already looked that shit up anyway.
我想聽你說
I wanna hear it from you.
我告訴你
So I do this...
我們就能回游戲廳
we go back to the arcade,
跟其他人探討這個計劃嗎
discuss the plan with the rest of them?
我不知道你指望我說什么
I don't know what you want me to say.
我們本來很親近  非常親近
We were close. Very close.
他是我最好的朋友
He was my best friend.
一輩子都在邪惡公司工作
Worked at Evil Corp his whole life.
本來是他們最棒的電腦工程師
He was one of the best computer engineers they had.
突然就被解雇了
And out of the blue, he got fired.
沒人知道原因
No one knew why.
然后有一天  他告訴我
Then one day he told me.
他得了白血病
He had leukemia.
還逼我不可以告訴別人
Made me swear to never tell anyone,
尤其是我媽
especially my mom.
我就沒說
So I didn't.
幾個月后
A few months go by...
他病得越來越重
he got sicker and sicker.
最后  我太擔心了
Finally, I got so worried...
就告訴了我媽
told my mom.
他知道后  大為光火
When he found out, he got pissed.
對我大吼大叫
Started yelling.
我記得我想去抱他  跟他道歉
I remember I tried to hug him, tell him I'm sorry, and...
他卻把我狠狠推開
kept shoving me away and shoved me so hard
結果我跌出了窗外
I fell backwards out the window.
把胳膊摔折了
I fell, and I broke my arm.
他此后再也沒跟我說過話
Never spoke to me after that.
甚至不肯看我
Couldn't even look at me.
甚至是他死的那晚
Even the night he died.
行了吧
We good?
我理解喪親之痛
I understand what it's like to lose a parent.
的確令人心碎
It's heartbreaking.
你有沒有想過或許他是對的
Did you ever think he was right?
關于什么
About what?
那他害你摔傷
Hurting you that day?
因為你對他做的事
For what you did to him?
你想過或許你是活該嗎
You ever think you deserved it?
我沒對他做什么
I didn't do anything to him.
我是想幫他
I was trying to help him.
你背叛了他的信任
For betraying his trust.
我才8歲
I was eight years ol--
你沒有遵守你們的神圣約定
You didn't commit to the sacred pact you'd formed.